Kopal Balachandan joins us chief
financial officer with ICC alumbad. He
joins us to talk about his quarterly
numbers and the way forward. Gopal good
morning thank you for joining us. Now
you mentioned earlier that the co will
remain uh in downward trajectory and for
f25 the co declined by 50 bips but for
Q4 it is similar to Q3 FI25. This
quarter we see higher claims ratio. What
led to this?
I think the only point that I would make
is uh uh there has been a regulatory
change that happened in the middle of
the year in the current financial period
and to that extent the numbers for FI25
may not be necessarily strictly
comparable with the FI24 numbers. Having
said that specifically to your point on
the quarter 4 combined ratios as what
you would have seen the reported
combined for Q4 this year was
102.5 viz let's say
102.3 but if I adjust for the change
that I talked about which happened in
the middle of the year my 102.5 would
have otherwise looked at
102.1 so even if you look at on a
sequential basis in terms of quarter 4
of last year to quarter 4 of the current
year adjusted for the change that the
guidelines that come into force, we have
actually seen some improvement in the
overall combined as well. But as we keep
saying uh the direction that we will
take from here on to your point on how
do we see possibly
fi I think we will continue to stay
focused in terms of our approach to
writing profitable book and hence
logically we should expect an
improvement in our combined issues even
going ahead and at the same time as we
have said the larger objective that we
will keep driving for is to try and see
how we can better the return on equity
that we are able to give to our
shareholders. So that's what we will
primarily focus on. Right. You also
guided for an ROE of about 16 to 20 uh%.
FI25 ROE is already at about 19%. What
factors do you think are going to help
you maintain and remain in this range?
Because specifically in Q4 we saw a dip
in your ROAS below 15%.
Yeah. So uh inherently if you look at
our business obviously is a lot more
cyclical and when I say cyclical a lot
of so if you look at our revenue streams
we generate profits through the core
insurance business but at the same time
given the fact that we there is al also
a lag between the time we collect
premium and there is a various outflows
that we have in terms of reinsurance
acquisition cost operating expenses
claims etc etc. So we also do have an
investment book through which we also
generate uh a reasonable return on the
investment portfolio. Now there
depending on how the market conditions
plays out is where you will see
opportunities playing out for us in
terms of uh there being any capital
gains in a particular quarter or not. Uh
specifically to your point on this
quarter four return on equity as at
maybe at a slightly lower level than
let's say on a fullear basis. Again I
again one we will keep urging everyone
to keep looking at the numbers more on
an annual basis that was that's more
partly reflective of how do we see
things playing out but specifically on
the point of quarter 4 which is what we
kind of explained on the earnings call
that we had yesterday as well to say
that quarter 4 of last year we had a
capital gains of roughly about 150
crores plus if you look at the current
quarter four how depending on how we saw
the markets play out the capital gains
was hardly a very very nominal number
and therefore that definitely tends to
have an impact in so far as the return
on equity for Q4 is concerned but this
has to be again looked at in the context
of quarter 3 for example quarter 3 of
the previous year had a capital gain of
roughly about 110 or 115 crores whereas
quarter 3 of this this year we had a
capital gain of almost about 275 crores.
So that's how we look at the market
opportunity wherever we see the markets
in our favor. So to that extent places
the treasury call we will be able to
kind of get some gains.
All right. But Mr. Balacha Chandan we
have also seen your investment income
declining in the quarter gone by. Help
us understand how should one expect uh
the investment income trajectory uh in
the coming quarters given the recent
rate cut.
Let me kind of first respond it in the
context of uh from a short-term
perspective. I think if you look at uh
specifically on the point that you had
on the bond side, uh we actually kind of
leveraged the opportunity which the
market had presented in the last couple
of years consequent to the high interest
rate regime and we actually kind of
leveraged that potential to be to expand
the duration of the portfolio that we we
were able to kind of write at. uh just
to kind of refresh at the end of March
22 our duration of the portfolio on the
bond side was slightly less than 4 years
uh today as you speak as at March 25
that duration of the book has increased
to almost 5.34 years so clearly we have
been able to go long and that's the
reason why our yield to maturity of the
book which used to be maybe a couple of
years back at less than 7% today the
yield to maturity of the portfolio is
running at 7.55%. So clearly we have
been able to leverage the opportunity
that the market had presented in so far
as the high interest rate regime is
concerned over the last couple of years
and rightfully so the portfolio today if
you were to see in the context of maybe
the point that you made with respect to
rate cut cycle that's again kind of
playing out to advantage. Uh so for
example if you see uh at mast 31 there
is a lot of unrealized gains that's
sitting on the bond book. uh so
obviously we will wait for how how much
more rate cuts happen in the future but
now coming to my longerterm point I
think if you look at from an ISIS number
standpoint historically if you look at
look at our last 24 years of our
existence on the entire investment book
we have been able to generate a realized
return anywhere between 8 to 9%. Uh
that's the kind of return that we've
exhibited over the last 24 years. uh in
terms of how things could play out
obviously will be a function of what
rate environment prevails.
Oop uh so even uh during our last
conversation you mentioned about the
need of price hike how much price hike
you've taken and how much more is
expected.
Yeah. So let me kind of talk this in the
context of maybe the commercial lines
first. Commercialized business is the
one that we exhibit so far as largely
corporates are concerned and there if
you see at the beginning of this year we
are called out to say that the market
could get a bit more uh competitive on
price and that's clearly evident if you
look at the outcome that has played out
specifically in one of the largest
segments of commercial lines which is
fire insurance. uh on a fullear basis
the segment has actually shown a
degrowth for the overall market and
that's the reason if you would have seen
the uh uh the growth of fire insurance
for the industry as a whole has been
significantly subdued uh at at slightly
very very low single-digit number in so
far as the market is concerned. uh but
the good news is what we had talked
about in the January earnings call as in
to say that these are segments which are
high on exposure and the ability of the
market to continue to see competitive
pricing for a very long period of time
possibly may not be sustainable and we
did indicate that there are early signs
of price action come back when we had
seen some of the January 1 renewals that
the corporates did for us in quarter 4.
So hence we were able to kind of clearly
seize the opportunity and vis the market
which still had a degrowth we kind of
grew positively. So our brand service
and technology clearly came into our uh
uh existence and we were able to kind of
grow faster at the time when the market
pricing started to see an improvement.
The same thing trend continues which
also we spoke in the call that we had
last evening as in to say that pretty
much majority of the corporates have
their renewal cycles on April 1 and
there again we have seen pretty much for
a very large portion of the commercial
lines business uh we have seen a
positive price action and therefore to
that extent that clearly augers very
well uh in so far as the pricing
environment is concerned
right thank you so much for joining
joining us today and highlighting how
your earnings of course and visibility
going forward is. will take. If you like
this video then like, share and
subscribe to ET now.